Come on!
加油
Look out girls, here we go.
坐稳 要冲下去了
Look to the left.
小心左边
Paddle!
用力划
-Can you see her? -Mummy!
- 看见她了吗 - 妈妈
Come on!
加把劲
Hold on!
抓稳了
Christ!
天哪
Yes!
万岁
-Mummy! -Hi, guys!
- 妈妈 - 你们好
Oh, Jessie. Yeah!
杰西 你好
That was amazing.
好惊险
-Oh, you girls were screaming. -All right, Jessie?
- 唉 你们叫声真大 - 走吧 杰西
-That wasn't so bad, was it? -No, it was a piece of piss.
- 玩得很爽吧 - 还凑合
Bitch!
混蛋
-Bit more, bit more. -Go on, Paul. Fish her out.
- 靠近一点 再近一点 - 保罗 去把她捞上来
There. Got you.
抓到了
-You all right? -Yeah.
- 你还好吧 - 是的
It's freezing. I can't feel my fingers.
冷死了 我手指都冻僵了
Heave!
拉上来
Jessie, Jessie.
杰西
Ah, come here. Oh, babe.
过来 宝贝
It was just amazing. Would you like to do that?
真不错 你想试试吗
Come on, Jessie, it's freezing. Let's go back to the car.
杰西 走吧 天气太冷 咱们回车里去
Go with your Daddy.
去 跟爸爸走
-I'll just help the girls. -All right.
- 我去帮帮她们 - 好的
It's OK, you go on. We can finish up here.
没关系 你走吧 这里交给我们
You sure? Thanks, guys. I'll see you at the hotel.
真的 谢谢 咱们旅馆见
See you.
回头见
Jess, shall I phone Rachel's mum?
杰西 要不要我给瑞琪尔的妈妈打个电话
See if Rachel wants to come to dinner on Thursday?
问问瑞琪尔周四晚上要不要来吃饭
Yeah? OK.
是吗 那好吧
When she comes round, she can help us plan your birthday party.
她来了以后还可以帮忙准备你的生日聚会
Are you going to invite any boys this time?
这次你要不要请些男孩子来
Are you OK? You seem a bit distant.
你没事吧 看起来心不在焉的
I'm fine.
我很好
Jess?
杰西
Jessie!
I'm sorry. She's gone.
对不起 她死了
-I'm sorry. -No!
- 对不起 - 不
No, no.
不 不会的
No, no, no.
不会的 不会的
She's gone, Sarah.
她去了 莎拉
片名: 黑暗侵袭
美国阿巴拉契亚山脉
一年以后
Well, it's mud, blood and beer...
有泥巴 有鲜血 有啤酒
or sweet Jesus.
还有天晓得什么东西
Great. Turn that shite off.
把那破玩意儿关掉
That's frightening.
想想就害怕
(欢迎来到查图嘎国家公园)
Listen, we don't have to do this, you know.
听着 咱们不必这样做 知道吗
We can head back and stay in town.
不如掉头回城里吧
Get wasted, go to a barn dance.
喝个烂醉 参加个舞会之类的
Now that is frightening.
你说的才叫人害怕
You're right, we don't have to do this.
你说得对 咱们不必这样做
But I'm not going to be the one to tell Juno.
但是我不会去和朱诺说
She's a piece of work, man. She always brings us out into the middle of...
她就是那种人 总把咱们带到…
Well, look at it.
你自己看吧
-She came to Scotland last year. -Yeah, and left pretty quickly.
- 去年她去了苏格兰 - 对 没过几天又离开了
Sarah! Beth!
莎拉 贝丝
Juno.
朱诺
You look fantastic.
你真漂亮
Ah, come here. Oh.
啊 过来抱抱
Let me look at you. Wow!
让我瞧瞧
Everything is going to be fine.
一切都会好起来的
Better. It's going to be great.
会比预料的还好
Becca and Sam can't wait to see you. Why don't you go in?
丽贝卡和珊姆等不及见你了 进去看看吧
-Give me these. -Yeah.
- 行李给我 - 好的
Thanks.
谢谢
-OK? -Yeah, OK.
- 你还好吧 - 是的
Ooh, very nice.
噢 真漂亮
-How is she? -Well, she's here.
- 她最近怎么样 - 就是现在这样
One step at a time, eh?
路要一步一步走 对吧
Hey, hey, hey! Who are you calling a fucking cheater?
嘿 妈的 你说谁作弊
I'm calling you a fucking cheater.
我说你他妈的作弊
Hello!
大家好
Hey!
你好
Hello.
-You do look really good. -Oh, you look amazing.
- 你气色真的不错 - 你真漂亮
-Hey! -Let me put the bags down.
- 你好啊 - 我先把行李放下
Oh, so nice to see you.
很高兴能够见到你
-We're starving. -OK, go, go.
- 我们快饿死了 - 好了 别聚着
-What have you got? -Er, well, there's a bit of...
- 有什么吃的 - 这个…还有一点…
Sam. Sam.
珊姆 珊姆
Thank you so much for your letter. It meant a lot to me.
谢谢你给我写信 对我帮助很大
Oh, Sarah, look, I'm so sorry that I couldn't be there.
唉 莎拉 对不起 我没能亲自过去
You know, mid-terms and...
因为忙着应付期中考试 还有…
You know, Sam is going to be Doctor Van Ney in like a year's time.
知道吗 大概一年以后珊姆就要做医生了
No!
不会吧
-Please tell me it's longer than that? -I am so proud of my little sister.
- 不会这么快吧 - 我真为我妹妹自豪
-Who wants a drink? -Yes! Me!
- 谁想喝酒 - 我
-Brandy shot? -Yeah, yeah.
- 白兰地 - 没错
-So, Beth... -Mm-hm?
- 那个 贝丝… - 啥
I hear it all starts falling apart past 25?
听说过了25岁 日子就变得一团糟
Is that what they teach you at medical school, yeah? To take the piss?
这是医学院里教的 教你惹人生气
Cheeky bitch!
贱人
Can anyone make me feel any older?
我简直要变成老太太了
-Oh, here we go. -Hello.
- 开始吧 - 你好
-Hi, you must be the teacher. -Beth, Sarah, this is Holly.
- 你好 你就是那个老师吧 - 贝丝 莎拉 这位是荷莉
Juno's protege.
朱诺是她的监护人
I always thought Juno would eat her young.
我一直以为朱诺会把她的孩子吃掉
I'm well able to handle myself, thanks very much.
我很会照顾自己 多谢
I've heard about you. You're that mentalist that jumps off buildings.
我听说过你的事 你是那个从楼顶往下跳的精神论者
-Base jumping. You should try it, seriously. -So you live in America now?
- 低空跳伞 强烈建议你也试一下 - 你如今住在美国
Ran out of things to jump off in Galway, you know.
在戈耳韦找不到可跳的建筑了
I'm always searching for the next big high.
我一直在寻找下一个目标
-Sure you'd know all about that. -Sorry?
- 你应该都知道了吧 - 什么
Juno showed me a photo of when you used to climb together.
朱诺给我看过你们俩一起登山的照片
I found this classic picture. Ah!
啊 这就是我找到的经典照片
Oh, no!
不会吧
-Look at the state of us! -Oh, my God. That's bad.
- 看看咱们从前的样子 - 天啊好难看
Sexy!
性感
Love each day.
热爱每一天
Used to be something Paul used to say.
保罗生前的口头禅
Anyway...cheers.
无论如何 干杯
Here's to our adventure.
为我们的探险干杯
Cheers.
干杯
Come on, light, you bastard.
快点上 王八蛋
So, have you done Boreham Caverns before?
你去过博莱翰岩洞群
I saw it in a book once. It's for tourists. It's not adventure.
在书上看到过一次 那是给游客玩的地方 不适合探险
Might as well have hand rails and a fucking gift shop.
里面可能还有围栏和该死的礼品店
If you're a caver, jumper, climber...
如果你是钻洞的 跳伞的 或者登山的
...you just do it and not give a shite.
探险就不能这么安逸
Or the thing that's bigger than you will get you.
否则迟早都会遭遇灾难
You want adventure, Holly? When have I ever let you down?
荷莉 你想要探险 我让你失望过吗
What?
什么
Holly, tomorrow is going to be awesome. OK?
明天让你如愿以偿
Take this. You need it.
拿着 你用得着
What about Josh, Sam? Are you guys still together?
珊姆 乔希怎么样了 你们还在一起
Kind of. Sort of.
算是吧
Different...shifts.
很少有时间在一起
Oh, my God.
老天爷啊
-Oh, my Jesus! -What do you think, eh?
- 天哪 - 你们有什么意见
Don't say a fucking word, all right?
别起哄好不好
It was a Christmas present.
这件是圣诞礼物
Shut up.
给我闭嘴
What about you Holly? Got a man?
荷莉呢 有男人了吗
I'm a sports fuck like Juno.
我和朱诺只爱运动
-What? -Rebecca, too, I think.
- 什么 - 我猜丽贝卡也是同一种人
But when I'm older, I want to have lots of babies.
但是等我老了 我要生一大群孩子
Beth, did Sarah tell you that...
贝丝 莎拉对你讲没讲过…
Wakey.
起床
I feel like road kill. Give me five minutes.
我累死了 等我五分钟
Five minutes.
五分钟
Good morning, my little ones. Wakey, wakey.
孩子们早上好 起床 起床
-Good morning. -Is that what you call it? It's fucking freezing!
- 早上好 - 好个屁 冻死了
Holly!
荷莉
We're leaving at seven. Don't be late.
七点出发 别迟到
Try that.
试试这个
The queen is dead.
女王已死
Long live...the fucking queen.
女王万岁
Beth, you're not driving.
贝丝 不能让你开车
-If you drive we'll never get there. -Paper, scissors, stone.
- 让你开车 咱们一辈子也到不了 - 猜拳决定
-Come on. -Oh, you're a dick.
- 来啊 - 真会耍花样
-Go on. -OK.
- 来吧 - 好
-There you go. -No, wait, babe. Best of three.
- 开始 - 不 等我数到三
I'll drive. Right?
我开车行了吧
Ladies, group photo.
女士们 拍张全家福
You'd better hurry it up. We're running late.
速度快一点 时间不多了
-I look like shit. -We all look like shit. Just give me a smile.
- 我这样子不好看 - 咱们都不好看 给我笑一个
-Hat? No hat? -No hat.
- 帽子呢 不戴帽子 - 不戴
-No hat, no hat. -All right.
- 不戴 不戴 - 好的
-Run, run, run, run. -Say "sausage"!
- 快快快 - 说"茄子"
Sausage!
茄…子
-Sarah, slow down a bit. -I'm having fun.
- 莎拉 慢一点 - 我玩得正爽
She's having fun.
她玩得正爽呢
Whoa! Turn, turn, turn there.
转弯 在那里转弯
-Let's off road. -Great.
- 开越野车喽 - 真棒
You should have some water.
你该喝点水了
Trying to set this watch is impossible. The buttons are too fucking small.
这破表总也调不好 按钮太小了
-Leave it alone. -Why do you wear it, anyway?
- 别管它了 - 干嘛非要戴它
-My boyfriend gave it to me, it's sentimental. -It's fucking mental.
- 这是我男朋友送的 有纪念意义 - 扯淡
Any guy that gave that to me, I'd dump him.
谁要送我这东西 我就甩了他
BETH: Juno, are you sure this is the right way?
朱诺 你确定是这条路
-Relax, I've never been lost in my life. -Marvellous.
- 放心 我从来没迷过路 - 不可思议
-So have you done these caves before? -No.
- 你以前探过这些岩洞吗 - 没
But they are only level two. Quite safe, don't worry.
但是别担心 这里的分级只有2级 相当安全
-I wasn't. -The only danger is that I might fall asleep.
- 我没担心 - 唯一的危险是我可能中途睡着
Boreham Caves. More like boredom caves.
博莱翰岩洞群 不如叫无聊岩洞群
-Nice parking. -Thanks.
- 停的漂亮 - 谢谢
This one time in Galway. when I free-climbed the cathedral,
有一次在戈耳韦 我用大教堂练攀岩
a priest chased me down the whole of the ground floor.
一个牧师追着我一直爬到第二层
That was brilliant.
他真不错
-I shouldn't have wasted the effort, though. -Holly, shut up.
- 但是我根本不该在那地方浪费时间 - 荷莉 别说了
Rebecca, leave her alone.
别管她 丽贝卡
OK, guys, let's get moving. We're running late.
好了 赶快出发吧 时间不多了
Come on, keep up.
快 跟上
-Hey, Holly, wait up. -Move it, short arse.
- 荷莉 等等 - 快走 矮矬子
-Oi, Carter, get to the back. -Come on, you lazy bastard.
- 快点赶上去 - 来啊 懒鬼
You finally caught up with me.
你终于跟上了
-Juno, are we there yet? -There's a river about half a mile ahead.
- 朱诺 还没到吗 - 前面半英里处有一条小溪
When we reach it, we follow it up to the mouth of the cave, OK?
沿着溪流走就能找到洞口
How does she know there's a river up ahead? I can't hear a thing.
她怎么知道有小溪 我听不见水声啊
She can probably smell it.
可能她是闻到的
She came up here last week to check the route out.
她上周来探过路
It's rule number one, file a flight plan and stick to it.
第一条规则: 制定一个计划 不要随意改变
-And rule number two? -Don't go wandering off.
- 第二条呢 - 不许离队
You think it's dark when you turn out the lights.
关掉灯的瞬间你会感觉四周很暗
Well, down there it's pitch black.
其实下面本来就一片黑暗
-You can get dehydration, disorientation... -Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 你有可能脱水 可能失去方向感 - 对 对 对
-...claustrophobia... -Blah, blah.
- 还有幽闭恐惧症 - 废话 废话 废话
...panic attacks, paranoia, hallucinations,
恐慌 妄想症 幻视
visual and aural deterioration...
视听障碍
Hey!
喂
Yeah, lovely, Holly. A real Kodak moment.
漂亮 荷莉来拍个特写
-Don't touch it. -You wouldn't want to piss it off.
- 别碰 - 别碰这东西
What do you think did that, Sam? A bear?
珊姆 你认为凶手是谁 熊
What is this? Nature Detectives?
问这个干嘛 你是野生侦探
It could have been Big Foot. Come on.
说不定是雪人干的 走吧
Sam, stop poking it with a fucking stick.
珊姆 别拿棍子戳
This is it.
就是这里
-You're having a laugh! -Afraid not.
- 就这么个东西 - 不止如此
I'm an English teacher, not fucking Tomb Raider.
我是英文老师 不是盗墓贼
You'll be fine.
别害怕
OK, Sarah, Beth, you're up next. Sam, stay with Becca.
莎拉和贝丝跟着我 珊姆 你和丽贝卡一起
Do what she does and you'll be fine.
照着她做 不会有事的
Holly, safety first. I don't want any stunts this time.
荷莉 安全第一 这次不许耍杂技
-You OK? See you down there. -No.
- 明白了 下面见 - 不对
Make sure your cow's tail is locked there and there.
把那边的绳子拴好
You hold on to this like that.
像这样握住
Look, I have done this before, you know?
知道吗 我这不是第一次
-I'm only looking after you. -And I appreciate it, in small doses.
- 我只想照顾你嘛 - 我领情了 只领那么一丁点
You gotta see this place.
下来看看
It's beautiful!
太美了
-You won't believe this, Beth. -Oh, shit!
- 贝丝 真难以置信 - 倒霉
Oh, my God, I'm gonna die.
上帝啊 我要死了
Ah, piece of piss.
小意思
Oh, my God!
天啊
It's incredible.
真不可思议
Clear!
没有危险
It's Holly.
是荷莉
Shit, move!
妈的 闪开
Holly, you do this safely, in order, following my lead. OK?
荷莉 安全第一 听我的命令 懂不懂
Take it slow and easy.
小心 慢慢来
-Juno. -Smart arse.
- 朱诺 - 小滑头
It's OK. It's OK. It's OK.
没事了 没事了
They're gone. They're gone now. Look.
都飞走了 你看
One bat, two bats.
一只蝙蝠 两只蝙蝠
50 bats.
50只蝙蝠
Holly, fuck off.
荷莉 闭嘴
Which way?
往哪边走
There's only one way out of this chamber and that's down the pipe.
要离开这个石室只有一条路 就是那条管道
OK.
好了
It's a drop.
有个台阶
OK?
没事吧
Holly, chuck us your bag.
荷莉 把你的袋子扔过来
Oh, my God!
天啊
Find anything good?
找到好东西了
-Jesus Christ! -Come on, let's eat.
- 天啊 - 来吃饭吧
-Holly, would you take a break? -I just want to take a few more shots.
- 荷莉 先停一下好不好 - 我再拍几段
This cave is a lot cooler than I thought.
洞里比我想的冷多了
Hey?
给你
Not hungry.
我不饿
Are you OK?
没事吧
Juno, I won't break. I'm fine.
我很好 朱诺
-I asked you for this. -I know.
- 我跟你说过这个 - 我知道
Um, Sarah?
莎拉
I haven't had a chance to say that I'm...
我一直没有机会说
really sorry I didn't stay around longer after the accident.
对不起 车祸之后我没有多陪你一段日子
Anyway...
无论如何
...we're all here for you now, OK?
现在我们又在一起了 好吗
Yeah.
很好
Look, sorry. I'm feeling a bit out of it. It's probably jet lag.
对不起 我有点心不在焉 可能是时差问题
-So I'm just going to take a look around, OK? -Yeah, OK.
- 我去四处转转 可以吗 - 去吧
Why don't you try and find us the way through, huh?
帮我们找找出口吧
Hey, don't go too far.
喂 别走太远
What's up with her? She looks like she's seen a ghost.
她怎么了 好象见了鬼似的
She's fine.
她很好
I've found the next passage!
我找到下一条路了
-That's it? It's a bit small, isn't it? -Hey, hey, hey!
- 就是这个 太窄了吧 - 喂喂喂
-I don't get this. -What?
- 我不明白 - 什么
This is not how I imagined it from reading the book.
这和我从书上看来的不一样
That's why I don't trust books. Leaves too much room for interpretation.
所以我不相信书本 上面写得太简略
Something wrong?
出问题了
-No. -It's nothing.
- 没 - 没有问题
I'm taking point, guys.
我断后
Careful. Just find the way through. We'll wait here.
探路的时候小心 我们在这里等着
Sarah?
莎拉
-Shit. -Are you still behind me?
- 妈的 - 你在我后面吗
Yes.
没错
Shit!
妈的
他妈的
Sarah? Guys, it's Sarah, I think she might be stuck.
莎拉 伙计们 是莎拉 她好象卡住了
I am stuck!
我卡住了
All right, Sarah. Calm down, just relax.
没事的 莎拉 冷静 放松
I can't fucking relax.
妈的我不能放松
Fuck, fuck!
靠
Sarah, you have to calm down
莎拉 你必须放松
and the only way you're going to do that is to breathe.
调整呼吸才能放松
OK, breathe slowly. Just keep breathing.
继续 慢慢呼吸
I can't. I can't.
我 我做不到
-I can't fucking breathe. -Sarah, OK, listen to me.
- 我喘不上气 - 莎拉 听我说
Just listen to my voice, yeah?
听着我的声音 好不好
Sarah, I'm coming. I'm coming back. OK? OK.
莎拉 我回来帮你 好吗
Sarah, OK?
还好吗 莎拉
Listen to me, keep breathing. OK? Hey.
听我说 继续呼吸 懂了
OK. OK. OK.
好 好 好
-Look here at me, Sarah, hey? -Help me.
- 看着我 莎拉 - 救命
What are you so worried about, Sarah? Look at me.
莎拉 看着我 你在害怕什么
OK, breathe. Breathe, OK?
很好 呼吸 呼吸
Hey, hey, hey. Listen to me.
听我说
-Listen to me. What are you so afraid of? -I can't fucking move!
- 听我说 你在害怕什么 - 妈的 我动不了
You can move. Sarah, look at me, look at me.
你可以动的 莎拉 看着我 看着我
The worst thing that could have happened to you has already happened...
你已经遭遇过最悲惨的事
...and you're still here.
如今还好好活着
This is just a poxy cave and there's nothing left to be afraid of, I promise.
这只是个石洞 里面没什么可怕的 我保证
OK? OK?
好吗 好吗
Hey. Hey, listen, listen.
听我说 听我说
Listen to me, you'll love this one. How do you give a lemon an orgasm?
听我说 给你讲个笑话 怎样才能让柠檬高潮
God damn it, let me hear you say it. How do you give a lemon an orgasm?
妈的 快回答 怎样才能让柠檬高潮
What do you do? You tickle its citrus.
该做什么 "爱抚"它的"把"
OK, that's better. Come on.
现在好些了吗 来
OK, OK. All right, we're going to move now. Take hold of my arm, all right?
好 咱们走 抓住我的胳膊 明白吗
We're going to move slowly. That's it, grab my arm, OK?
咱们慢慢来 抓着我的胳膊 明白
OK, come on.
好 来吧
Just slowly. Pull on me, OK? OK, come on.
慢慢跟我来 好吗 走
The rope bag. I forgot the rope bag.
背包 我忘了拿背包
OK.
好吧
OK, fuck the rope bag. OK, move, now!
去他妈的背包 赶快爬
Now!
快
Hurry up!
快点
Sarah, come on!
快点啊莎拉
Sarah, keep hold of the rope!
莎拉 抓住绳子
Sarah?
莎拉
-Are you OK? -I'm all right.
- 你没事吧 - 没事
Is everybody OK? Is everybody OK?
大家都还好吗
-Don't fucking touch me. -Rebecca?
- 别碰我 - 丽贝卡
I'm here, I'm OK. Beth, are you injured?
- 我在这里 我很好 - 贝丝 你受伤没
No, I'm fine.
没 我也没事
Nobody move until the dust has settled.
灰尘落定以前谁也不许动
Don't worry, Juno, we're not going anywhere.
放心吧朱诺 我们哪也去不了
You might be right about that.
这句说得一点也没错
Jesus.
天啊
So what's the story now?
现在怎么办
According to the guidebook, this cave system has three ways out.
根据导游手册上说的 这个岩洞群有三个出口
This is just one of them. Isn't that right, Juno?
这只是其中一个而已 对不对 朱诺
Juno, that's right, isn't it?
朱诺 对不对啊
Check the book.
查一下书
-I didn't bring it. -What?
- 我没带 - 什么
No point.
带了也没用
For Christ's sake, Juno.
朱诺 怎么会这样
I knew it. I knew this wasn't right.
我就知道事情不对
You filed a flight plan to mountain rescue?
你在山区救援组登记了吧
If we don't report in, they'll come looking for us.
如果我们不去报到 他们会来搜救
That's how it's supposed to work except I put in a flight plan for Boreham Caverns
如果我们来的是博莱翰岩洞群 他们确实会来
and this isn't Boreham Caverns, is it, Juno?
不过这里不是博莱翰岩洞群 对吧 朱诺
We're in the wrong fucking cave?
咱们走错山洞了
Holly was right. Boreham Caverns was a tourist trap.
荷莉说的对 博莱翰岩洞群是坑骗游客的
Don't try and pin this fucking shite on me!
别跟我说这些屁话
This is not caving. This is an ego trip.
这不是探险 是拐骗
Rebecca, I didn't know this was going to happen.
丽贝卡 我没想到会发生这种事
This is exactly what we believe in.
我们一直认为
We said, if there's no risk, what's the point?
如果没有风险 就没有意思了
Don't try and justify this.
不要狡辩
Where... Where are we?
我们在哪
It hasn't got a name. It's a new system.
这是个全新的岩洞系统 还没有名字
I wanted us all to discover it.
我想让我们共同享有发现权
No-one's ever been down here before.
从来没有人下来过
-You're fucking kidding me. -Oh, God!
- 妈的你开玩笑吧 - 哦老天
-How the hell do we get out? -There may not be a way out.
- 咱们怎么出去 - 可能没有出口
Look, there's no going back now.
现在已经没法回头了
We have to find a way out of this chamber and keep pushing forward.
我们只能继续前进 寻找出口
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
你以为你在干嘛
We all trusted you. You told me this was going to be good for Sarah.
我们都信任你 你说探险是为了莎拉好
Have you any idea what she's been through?
你了解她的心情吗
No, cos you couldn't get away fast enough, you selfish cow.
不了解 因为你掉头就跑了 自私的婊子
You know what, Beth?
贝丝 你知道吗
We all lost something in that crash.
那次车祸 我和她都失去了某些东西
Just get us out of here.
快带我们出去
Look, cave systems sometimes break ground. It's a small chance.
岩洞有时会崩塌 这个概率很小
But if we stay here, we'll die.
但是如果我们留在这里 就一定会死
Let's go.
咱们走吧
-Wait! -What?
- 等等 - 怎么
Don't move, Sam. Just don't move.
别动 珊姆
Stay right there.
站在原地
Oh, shit. No more.
妈的 没路了
Thanks, Beth.
谢谢 贝丝
Now I know how far down it is.
我试试它有多深
So, what now?
现在怎么办
One of us has to get all the way across there so they can rig a line for you guys.
得有一个人过到对面去 扯一条线 让其他人也过去
I have three cams, I need at least three more. Where's the other rope bag?
我有三个凸轮 至少再有三个才够 背包呢
Where is it?
哪去了
We lost it, when the cave collapsed.
洞穴崩塌的时候丢了
Sorry.
对不起
Help me.
帮我一把
Come on, Becca.
加油 丽贝卡
-Aargh! -You got it.
成功了
Come on, come on.
加油 加油
Come on, Rebecca.
加油啊 丽贝卡
加油 丽贝卡
What are you waiting for?
你等什么呢
-Fuck. -Are you OK?
- 靠 - 你怎么了
What's wrong?
有问题吗
It's nothing. I'm all right.
没事 我很好
OK.
好吧
All right, more slack.
好了 放绳子过来
More slack, thanks.
再放一些 谢谢
Fuck!
妈的
-OK. -Well done.
- 好了 - 干得漂亮
OK. Throw me the right rope.
好 把右边的绳子抛过来
OK.
好
准备好了
Come on.
过来
Yeah!
来了
-Now, you make it look easy. -Yeah, well, you make it look hard.
- 这不是很容易嘛 - 你刚好相反
-Oh. -Don't look down, Beth. Keep going.
别往下看 贝丝 一直向前
-Just keep going. -You're OK. You're safe.
- 继续爬 - 放心 很安全的
Good. There you go.
好 上来了
Was this about me or you?
到底是为了你 还是为了我
It's about us, getting back to what we used to be.
为了我们 为了让我们恢复过去的样子
I wanted us to claim this place, name it.
我们要申请这地方的发现权 给它命名
I thought maybe your name.
我想可能是用你的名字
Or maybe yours.
也可能是你的名字
You're doing well. Come on.
干得不错 继续
Come on.
过来
There you are. Come on, give me your hand.
到了 把手给我
Juno?
朱诺
We'll need everything we've got.
已经用不到这些了
Haul it in.
收回去
Yes!
成功
Reach.
伸手
Reach out.
用力
Juno!
朱诺
No!
不
Juno, it's OK, we've got you.
朱诺 放心 拉住你了
OK, pull!
好 往上拉
-Sam! -Holly, let me pass.
- 珊姆 - 荷莉 让我过去
Rebecca, show me your hand.
丽贝卡 把手给我
Let go, let go.
放松 放松
-What does it mean? -It means we're not the first.
- 这是什么意思 - 意思是 我们不是第一个来的
It's a piton, right?
是个岩钉
If cavers were here, there's a better chance of us getting out.
如果有其他人来过 我们找到出口的概率会更大
This equipment is at least 1 00 years old. No-one uses stuff like this any more.
这东西至少有100年了 如今没人用这种东西
Besides, if anyone had been down here and made it out,
另外 如果有人来过这里而且又出去了
they would have named it already.
这洞穴就早该有名字了
Becca, are you OK?
丽贝卡 你怎么样
I'll live.
还没死
Holly, how does it look?
荷莉 前面的路怎么样
It's tight again, but I can get through.
又变窄了 但是我能过去
OK, keep going. We'll be right behind you.
好的 你先走 我们随后
Hey, there's something down here.
喂 这下边有什么东西
Guys, it's amazing, but the batteries on our lights will run out.
真漂亮 但是咱们的灯要没电了
-So I suggest we keep moving. -Wait a minute. Wait.
- 按我说 咱们继续走吧 - 等等 等一下
-What is it, Beth? -Juno, light up one of your flares.
- 什么事 贝丝 - 朱诺 给我一个照明弹
-We don't have time for this. -Just light a flare.
- 没有必要 - 扔一个照明弹
-Really lovely, Beth, but it's fucking useless. -No, look at it. What do you see?
- 真漂亮 但是这东西没用 贝丝 - 不 仔细看 你看到什么
You've got the mountain, the cave...
山脉 洞窟
and there's two entrances.
一共有两个开口
-You are a fucking genius. -I have my moments.
- 你是天才 - 我也有走运的时候
-This means there's another way out? -Let's find out.
- 就是说 还有条路可以出去 - 咱们找找看
Come on!
走吧
-Bastard! -Which way?
- 混蛋 - 该走哪边
Holly, give me your lighter.
荷莉 打火机给我
-Come on. -Here.
- 快点 - 给
Fuck!
靠
-Come on! Come on! -Shit!
- 快 赶快 - 倒霉
-That one! -Hey! Holly!
- 这一条 - 喂 荷莉
Holly, slow down!
荷莉 慢慢来
Holly! Careful!
小心 荷莉
Daylight! I can see daylight!
日光 我看见日光了
Holly! Careful! Slow down!
荷莉 小心 慢一点
Holly, it's not daylight!
荷莉 那不是日光
-Help me! -Hold on!
- 救命 - 坚持住
Guys! Hold...
抓住
Holly!
荷莉
Sam! Get down here!
珊姆 快过来
Holly!
荷莉
Holly! Answer me!
荷莉 回答我
I think I hurt my leg!
我的腿好象断了
Don't move! We're coming down to you.
别动 我们下来救你
Someone better get down here!
快下来救我
-Oh, that's fucking disgusting. -Beth! Not here, not now!
- 真恶心 - 贝丝 现在不行
We need help. Everybody grab a corner. We need to move her out of the water.
每人抓一个角 把她从水里抬出来
Nice and easy now. And...lift!
全身放松 预备 抬
-You fuckers! -Juno, find something to make a splint out of.
- 你们这群王八蛋 - 朱诺 去找些东西做夹板
-It's OK, I've got her. -Hey, Juno, use one of the ice axes.
- 好 按住她 - 朱诺 把你的破冰斧给我一把
You'll be all right, sweetheart.
你会好起来的 宝贝
OK.
好了
-Sarah! -Juno, I'm gonna need your help here.
- 莎拉 - 朱诺 我还需要你帮忙
-Sarah! -Juno!
- 莎拉 - 朱诺
Take hold of her arm. You'll have to hold her down.
你们抓住她的胳膊 把她按住
What are you gonna do?
你要干什么
I need to dress the wound and rig up a splint, but I can't while the bone is protruding.
断骨支出来了 没法缝合伤口 也不能上夹板
I need to push it back in.
我要把它推回去
-I hate you. -I know.
- 我恨你 - 我知道
Do it.
来吧
Bite down on this.
咬住这个
-Keep hold of her. -Just fucking bite down, OK?
- 按住她 - 紧紧咬着 明白
Go!
开始
Come on!
加把劲
Just keep biting down, baby.
用力咬着
Come on.
用力
OK, someone get me a medical kit.
好了 帮我拿医药箱来
OK, OK, OK. Calm down. It'll be all right.
好了 好了 冷静一下 全都过去了
What are you doing?
你在干什么
I just saw something ahead in the tunnel.
我刚刚看见隧道那边有人
Sarah, I promise you, I'm gonna get you out of here.
莎拉 我保证 一定会带你出去
But I can't do it unless you're with me.
但是你不肯配合的话我也没办法
Sarah?
莎拉
Sarah!
Sarah, look at me.
莎拉 看着我
There's nothing there.
那里什么也没有
That's the best I can do.
我能做的就这么多
It'll hurt like hell and you can't put any weight on it, but at least you can move.
你会疼得想死 这条腿也不能承受任何重量 但是至少你可以走路了
They combed these mountains centuries ago. Anyone trapped would be a skeleton now.
他们几百年前就搜过山 不管谁被困在这里 如今也变成骷髅了
-That is just what it looked like. -What?
- 看上去就是这样 - 什么事
-Sarah thinks she saw someone. -Saw what?
- 莎拉认为她看见人了 - 看见什么
I don't think l saw someone, I saw someone.
没有"认为" 我就是看见人了
No, you heard something and saw what you wanted to see.
不 你听见了什么声音 然后骗自己说那是人
-It's the dark. It plays tricks on people. -I can describe exactly what I saw.
- 是黑暗让你产生了错觉 - 我能详细描述出看见的东西
-What did you see? -A man. I saw a man.
- 你看见的是什么 - 男人 我看见一个男人
-Are you sure? -Yes!
- 你确定 - 是的
And it's not the first time. I thought I saw someone before, but now I'm sure.
从前我有过错觉 但这次我敢肯定是真的
Look, if there is somebody down here, then maybe they can help get us out.
如果这下边有人 也许他们能帮我们出去
Sarah, there's no-one down here. Forget about it!
莎拉 算了吧 这下面没有人
Hey, we have to get Holly out of here.
咱们得把荷莉搬出去
OK? This is all that matters right now.
这才是眼下最重要的事
-Beth! -It's OK.
- 贝丝 - 算了吧
Is it? Fuck!
算了 见鬼
You've got to keep warm.
你要注意保暖
Why are we walking away? There was daylight back there.
为什么走这个方向 后面就有日光啊
It wasn't. It was phosphorus in the rock.
不是日光 是岩石的磷光
We're two miles underground, the only light down here is ours.
咱们在地下两英里深的地方 唯一的光就是电灯光
Argh! Well, it looked like fucking daylight to me.
在我看真像日光
Right tunnel!
右面的隧道
I got you. OK?
我来帮你
Jesus! What is this place?
老天 这是什么地方
Holly, where's the infrared button?
荷莉 红外线模式的开关在哪
Dead animals.
动物遗体
Hundreds of them.
好几百具
This is not good, guys.
这可不是什么好地方
Can we get out of here? Which way?
快离开吧 走哪条路
-I don't know. -What do you mean, you don't know?
- 我不知道 - 你不知道 什么意思
There's no breeze. It could be any one of these tunnels. Take your pick.
这里没有风 每条隧道都可能是出口 你们选吧
Oh, fuck it! Hello!
去他妈的 有人吗
-Please! -Is there anybody there?
- 小点声 - 有没有人
Hello!
有人吗
It's there! It's up there! It's there on the roof!
在那里 上面 在洞壁顶上
Fucking hell, did you see...? What the fuck was that?
你看见了吗 那是什么鬼东西
I don't know! It moved so fast, I could barely see it!
不知道 它动作太快 我几乎看不见
-I've never seen anyone climb like that! -I told you I saw someone!
- 我从没见过会这样爬墙的 - 我说过我看见人了
-That was not a human being! -Screw this.
- 那不是人类 - 少废话了
Let's take our chances and pick a tunnel. Move!
碰运气吧 选一条路 快走
What's happening?
怎么了
Oh, shit! It's circling us.
见鬼 它围着咱们转
-Where is it? -This way! Move!
- 它在哪里 - 那条路 快走
-Holly! We've got to move. We've got to move. -Come on! Move it!
- 荷莉 咱们走 - 快啊 快走
Come on, Holly! Move it! Let's go!
快 荷莉 走路啊 赶快
Juno, the flare! Get rid of it!
朱诺 把照明弹扔掉
Holly, keep moving, come on!
荷莉 坚持住 快走
Holly! Holly!
荷莉 荷莉
Sarah!
莎拉
Holly!
荷莉
Sarah!
莎拉
Sarah! Run!
莎拉 快跑
Sarah!
莎拉
Get off!
滚
Get away, you fucker!
滚远点 王八蛋
Don't leave me.
别丢下我
Oh, fuck. My battery's gone dead.
靠 我的电池没电了
Where are they?
它们去哪了
What's happened to the others?
其他人呢
Becca, please say we're gonna get out of here.
丽贝卡 求求你 告诉我说咱们能出去
OK. OK.
好吧好吧
OK.
谢谢
Go. Go!
走吧 走
Mummy. Mummy.
妈妈 妈妈
If you're really ready...
如果你真的准备好了
Turn the light off.
把灯关掉
Quiet.
别出声
Sarah! Sarah!
莎拉 莎拉
Sarah!
莎拉
It can't see us.
它看不见咱们
Sam? Becca?
珊姆 丽贝卡
Becca!
丽贝卡
-Becca! -It's Juno.
- 丽贝卡 - 是朱诺
Becca!
丽贝卡
The noise she's making, she'll bring every one of those things down on her head.
这么大嗓门 她会把所有怪物全引过去的
As long as it's not on mine.
只要别引过来就行
Becca!
丽贝卡
Sam!
珊姆
Anyone?
有人吗
Sam!
珊姆
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起
Fuck. OK.
好
OK.
好的
很好
It's all clear.
没有怪物
Sam, run!
快跑 珊姆
We heard you crying for Sarah.
我们听见你喊莎拉
Where are the others?
其他人呢
They... They took Holly.
荷莉被它们杀了
Beth...
贝丝
Beth's dead.
贝丝死了
Sam...
珊姆
...what is that thing?
那东西是什么
I don't know. Well, it does look human.
我不大清楚 看起来很像人类
Come on, we need to find the way out before those things find us.
在被那些东西找到之前 我们要找到出口
No.
不
Sam, tell us what we're fighting.
珊姆 告诉我 我们在和什么东西战斗
Well...
好吧
...they're totally blind.
这东西完全没有视觉
And judging from what we've seen, I'd say they use sound to hunt with.
根据我们所看到的 我认为它们根据声音寻找猎物
Like a bat.
和蝙蝠相似
And they've evolved perfectly to live down here in the dark.
它们进化得非常适应地底生活
Whatever they are, they go to the surface to hunt.
不管它们是什么 它们会去地表狩猎
And they bring their food back down here to eat, through an entrance.
然后通过一个洞口把猎物带回来
Listen, if we can stay quiet enough and evade these fuckers...
听着 我认为 如果我们能悄悄避开这些怪物
...I think I found the way out.
就有可能找到出口
You think?
你这么想
The climbing gear we found...
还记得我们找到的那些攀岩工具吗
...whoever brought that down here marked their route.
留下这些东西的人标出了他们的路线
-I found those markings. -Well, what are we waiting for?
- 我找到了那些标记 - 那还等什么
Sarah.
莎拉
I'm not leaving without Sarah.
没有莎拉我不走
Sarah!
莎拉
Oh, God.
上帝
Oh, God. No.
上帝啊 不
Sarah...
莎拉
I'm getting you out of here.
我带你出去
Don't touch me. Don't touch me.
别碰我 别碰我
I heard Juno calling me.
我听见朱诺在叫我
I'm gonna go and find her, and we're gonna come back and get you out.
我去找她 然后回来带你走
-No, stay away from her. -What?
- 不 不要靠近她 - 怎么
-She did this to me. -What?
- 她把我弄成这样 - 怎么会
She left me.
她把我丢下
No, she didn't. No.
不 她不会的 不
Sarah...
莎拉
Don't trust her.
别相信她
You find your own way out.
你自己找路出去
It's OK. It's all right.
放心 一切都会好的
I'm not gonna leave you, Beth. I'm not gonna leave you.
我不会离开你的 贝丝 绝不离开你
I'm not leaving you here, OK?
我不会离开你 好吗
Come here. Beth!
起来 贝丝
This is Juno's.
这是朱诺的
It's from Paul.
保罗送给她的
Oh, no.
哦 不
Sorry.
对不起
Please... Oh, that's them. Please, come with me.
它们来了 快 快跟我走
Please.
求求你
Sarah...
莎拉
...don't leave me like this.
杀了我吧
No, please don't ask me to do that.
不 别让我做这种事
-Please. -I can't. I can't do that.
- 求求你 - 我做不到
I can't do that.
我做不到
Please.
求你了
OK.
好吧
Close your eyes.
闭上眼睛
Hurry! Move!
快 快跑
Sarah?
莎拉
Look, she's dead, Juno. We can't wait for her.
看吧 她死了 朱诺 咱们不能等她
Come on!
走啊
Sarah!
莎拉
Sarah?
Run!
快跑
Oh, fuck!
妈的倒霉
Juno, stop her! I'll be right behind you!
朱诺 拦住她 我马上跟上
Sam! What are you doing?
珊姆 你干什么
Come back!
回来
Becca!
丽贝卡
You haven't got enough rope!
你的绳子不够长
Sam! Turn around!
珊姆 快回来
-What are you doing? Turn around! -Sam, baby!
- 你要干嘛 快回来 - 珊姆
-Sam! Sam! -Sam, turn around. You can come back.
- 珊姆 珊姆 - 珊姆 赶快回来 还来得及
Please, baby, listen to me. Please!
求你了 听我的吧 求你
Sam!
珊姆
No!
不
What are you doing?
你要干什么
Sam!
珊姆
Sam! No!
珊姆 不要
What happened to you?
你怎么了
Rebecca?
丽贝卡呢
What about Beth?
贝丝呢
Didn't make it.
她没能挺过来
You saw her die?
你亲眼见她死的
Come on.
走吧
Come on. Come on.
过来啊 来啊
No! No!
不 不要
Oh, God!
上帝啊